It's the truth that haunts us
The River King is a drama, mystery, thriller film directed by Nick Willing.
Abel Grey is sent to investigate the death of a boy from an
exclusive local school, who is found floating in the river.
Fearing scandal, the school insists it was suicide.
But after discovering from the boy's girlfriend, Carlin, that he was being badly bullied, Abel suspects that a dangerous
schoolboy initiation has gone horribly wrong and he secretly solicits the help of a sympathetic teacher, Betsy.
He is warned off the investigation by his boss, as the school is a
generous benefactor to the Police benevolent fund.
Abel, however, cannot let the case go, not only because his own brother committed suicide years before, but also it
seems that the spirit of the dead boy is leaving them clues as to what really happened that night.
Abel Grey, played by Edward Burns.
Betsy Chase, played by Jennifer Ehle.
Joey Tosh, played by John Kapelos.
Carlin Leander, played by Rachelle Lefevre.
Joey's Son, played by Bruce Murphy.
Eric Herman, played by Julian Rhind-Tutt.
King Kong is a 2005 epic monster film directed,
co-written, produced by Peter Jackson.
It is the ninth entry in the King Kong franchise and the second remake of the
1933 film of the same title, the first being the 1976 remake.
The film stars Naomi Watts, Jack Black, Adrien Brody, Thomas Kretschmann, Colin
Hanks, Jamie Bell, and Andy Serkis as the motion capture of Kong.
Set in 1933, it follows the story of an ambitious and unscrupulous filmmaker who tricks
his cast and hired ship crew into travelling to mysterious Skull Island.
There they encounter various prehistoric creatures and a legendary giant
gorilla known as Kong, whom they capture and take to New York City.
Development began in early 1995, when Universal Pictures approached
Jackson to direct the remake of the original 1933 film.
The project stalled in early 1997, as several ape and giant monster-related films were under production
at the time and Jackson planned to direct The Lord of the Rings film series instead.
As the first two films in the Rings trilogy became commercially successful, Universal went back to Jackson in early
2003, expressing interest in restarting development on the project, to which Jackson eventually agreed.
Filming for King Kong took place in New Zealand
from September 2004 to March 2005.
It was the most expensive film ever produced at the time of its release, as its budget
climbed from an initial $150 million to a then record-breaking $207 million.
King Kong premiered at New York City on 5 December 2005, and was theatrically released
in New Zealand on December 13 and in the United States on 14 December.
The film received critical acclaim, and eventually appeared in several top ten lists for 2005; it was praised for the special effects,
performances, sense of spectacle and comparison to the 1933 original, though some criticisms were raised over its 3-hour runtime.
It was a commercial success, grossing over $557 million, and became the fourth-highest-grossing film in
Universal Pictures history at that time and the fifth-highest-grossing film of 2005.
It also generated $100 million in DVD sales upon its
home video release in March 2006.
It won three Academy Awards for Best Sound Editing, Best
Sound Mixing and Best Visual Effects.
A tie-in video game was released alongside the film, which
also became a commercial and critical success.
The tone is intense and lighthearted and emotional.